(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-07T02:11:08.704305",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
火の用心じゃー！
Beware of fire!
あらあら？めらめら？熱干めらー！！
Oh dear? Flaring up? Atsuchi Mera!
ホロライブ アソビ★まわり隊 ご利益担当の火消し屋サラマンダー
The blessing-bringer of the Hololive Play-Around Squad, the firefighter salamander,
熱干めらなのじゃ！
Atsuchi Mera!
みなさん！はじめまして！！
Nice to meet you, everyone!
2026年9月24日にホロライブからデビューした
I debuted from Hololive on September 24, 2026,
ピカピカの新人VTuberなのじゃー！
as a sparkling new VTuber!
今日はわしの自己紹介動画を撮っていこうと思うのじゃ！
Today, I'm going to record my self-introduction video!
わしのこと「どんな子かなー？」とか気になってたり
If you're wondering what kind of person I am,
「人間じゃないの？」とか
like "Is she not human?"
「なんで髪の毛燃えてるの？」とか
or "Why is her hair on fire?"
「ホロライブのオーディションを受けた時の話」とかもしようかなって思ってるので
I'll also talk about my Hololive audition, so...
この動画を見てわしのこといっぱい知ってくれたら嬉しいのじゃ！
I hope you learn a lot about me through this video!
ということで動画スタート！！
And with that, let's start the video!
名前は、熱干めら。
My name is Atsuchi Mera.
「ねっせん」じゃないのじゃ！
It's not "Nessen"!
「あっちち」って読むのじゃ。
It's read as "Atsuchi".
「千度の熱」と書いて「熱干(あっちち)」
Written with the characters for "thousand-degree heat".
良い名前なのじゃ！
It's a great name!
そして「めら」、メラメラの「めら」なのじゃ！
And "Mera" is from the crackling sound "mera-mera"!
火が燃えてる時のオノマトペ？擬音？みたいなやつなのじゃ！
It's like an onomatopoeia or sound effect for fire!
漢字がちょっと分かりづらいのと、あと辞書で一発で出てこないので
The kanji is hard to read and doesn't show up in dictionaries,
めら組のお主らは
so all you members of the Mera-gumi,
「熱干(あっちち)」をスマホとかで辞書登録みたいなのができたはずじゃから
please register "Atsuchi" in your phone's dictionary,
それで辞書登録して、いつでも「熱干(あっちち)」を呼び出せるようにしてほしいのじゃ！
so you can easily type it whenever you want!
そして、お主らが気になってるであろう種族！
Next up, the species you're probably curious about!
わしは、サラマンダーなのじゃ！
I am a salamander!
見てこのツノ。ツノ。
Look at these horns! Horns!
あと、しっぽなのじゃー！
And my tail!
どうかのぉ？可愛いのぉ？
What do you think? Isn't it cute?
サラマンダーとは、火を司る精霊らしいのじゃ！
A salamander is a spirit that controls fire!
わしの髪の毛からもね、こうやって炎が出ておるじゃろ。
See how fire comes out of my hair like this?
これはね、体内の熱をどこかから出さないとね
This is because if I don't release my body heat,
わしが火を吹いちゃって、周りを火だらけにしちゃう、大変なことにしちゃうから
I'll breathe fire and set everything around me ablaze,
こうやって髪から出すことで、火を暴発しないようにしておるんじゃ。
so I let it out of my hair to prevent accidental explosions.
わし的には正直人間と変わらんくね？と思っているところがあって
Personally, I feel like I'm barely any different from humans.
火に強いとは言いつつも、火傷はするのじゃ。
Even though I'm resistant to fire, I still get burned.
手とか指とかは火傷しないんじゃけど、粘膜、粘膜は結構火傷しちゃうから
My hands and fingers don't burn, but my mucous membranes easily do.
それこそベロとか、あったかいココアとか飲むときは
So like my tongue, when I drink hot cocoa,
ベロ火傷しちゃって熱くなるのじゃ。
I burn my tongue and it hurts!
あと、炎属性なんじゃが、夏はめちゃくちゃ暑いのじゃ！
Also, despite my fire element, summer is super hot for me!
日本の夏、やばいのじゃ。
Japanese summers are brutal.
湿度とかもあるからかな？やばいから、熱中症になるのじゃ、熱中症。
Maybe it's the humidity? It's so bad I get heatstroke!
サラマンダーなのに。
Even though I'm a salamander.
熱中症とか火傷とかそういうのならないようにすればいいのに。
I wish I were completely immune to heatstroke and burns.
わしはあと火を吹いたりできるのじゃ！
But I can also breathe fire!
火を吹くところはね、デビューしたとき、あの情報解禁のときに上げてた映像に
You can see me breathing fire in the PV released
火をね、吹いてるアニメーションがあってね、それを見てほしいのじゃ。
when my debut was announced, so please check it out!
わしのカッコいいところが見れるかもしれんのじゃ！
You might get to see my cool side!
わしの年齢は、415歳！
My age is 415 years old!
長生きなのじゃー。
I'm long-lived~!
生年月日で言うと、1611年の4月16日生まれなのじゃ。
In terms of birthdate, I was born on April 16, 1611.
何年何月何日とか言ったんじゃが
I just gave the exact year, month, and day,
厳密には覚えてなくて、だいたい江戸時代だった気がするのじゃ。
but I don't actually remember exactly. I just feel like it was around the Edo period.
あとわしは良い子じゃから
Also, since I'm a good kid ("yoi-ko"),
415(よいこ)歳ってことにしようと思って、
I decided to be 415 ("yoi-ko") years old,
415歳ってことにしようと思って
I decided to go with 415 years old,
そっから逆算することによって、1611年生まれになったということじゃ。そういうことじゃ。
and by reverse-calculating from that, I ended up being born in 1611! That's how it is.
全部うる覚えなのじゃ！
It's all a vague memory!
そんな何百年も前のことを覚えてるわけないのじゃ！
There's no way I'd remember things from hundreds of years ago!
だいたい400歳ぐらいじゃと思って、いただければ良いのかなと思うのじゃ。
So just think of me as roughly 400 years old!
そして400年前、わしが生まれたての頃、何をしてたかというと
So, what was I doing when I was newly born 400 years ago?
火消しという職業をしていたのじゃ！
I worked as a firefighter (hikeshi)!
火消しってのは現代で言うところの消防団みたいな、文字通り火事を消すのじゃ。
A hikeshi is like a modern-day volunteer fire department; literally putting out fires.
わしはサラマンダーじゃから、ある程度火には強くて
Since I'm a salamander, I'm somewhat resistant to fire,
だから火事が大変になってるところにも行って、わしがこう率先して火を消していくのじゃ。シュッシュッシュッって。
so I'd go to major fires and take the lead in putting them out.
そしてわしは、纏持ち(まと持ち)というものをやっていたのじゃ。
And my job was to be the standard-bearer (matoimochi).
なんか火消しっていう、火を消す人たちがいるじゃろ。
Among the firefighting crew,
その中でも「纏」っていうね、デカい棒に何かついててね、振るやつがあるのじゃ。それをね、持ってね、いたのじゃ。
there's a "matoi", which is a big decorated pole that you wave. I was the one holding that.
当然人間の寿命よりもわしの寿命の方が長いから
Naturally, my lifespan is much longer than a human's,
仲良かった人間たちがみんないなくなっちゃって、しばらく1人でいるかーと思って
so all my human friends eventually passed away. I figured I'd live alone for a while,
その後は山に篭ってたのじゃ。200年くらい。
and retreated to the mountains for about 200 years.
山に篭ってる間にしてたこと。
What I did while living in the mountains...
寝て、起きて、食べて、寝てたのじゃ！
Sleep, wake up, eat, and sleep!
200年くらいずーーっと寝て起きて食べて寝ての生活をしてたのじゃ。
For 200 years, I literally just slept, ate, and slept.
山から下りて、人間と一緒に暮らし始めてから、今まで20年くらい
Since coming down from the mountains and living with humans, about 20 years have passed,
人間と共に生活をしてきたのじゃ。人間20年選手っていうことじゃな。
and I've lived alongside humans. I guess I'm a 20-year veteran of human life!
なんでわしが人間と暮らし始めたかという話なんじゃが
As for why I started living with humans,
わしが山で生活してた時にの、山にスマホが捨ててあったんじゃよ。
when I was in the mountains, there was a discarded smartphone there.
「スマホおもれー！」と思って、触ってたら
I thought, "Smartphones are so fun!" and while playing with it,
わしは匿名掲示板を発見したんじゃよ。
I stumbled upon an anonymous message board.
匿名掲示板で、「これ、会話できるのではー！」と思って
On that anonymous board, I realized, "Wait, I can talk to people here!"
そこに書き込みとかをしてたんじゃよ。
And I started posting comments there.
そう、人間と話せるの嬉しくて
Yeah, I was so happy to talk to humans.
拾ってすぐやり始めたから
Since I started doing it right after picking it up,
その何だろう、ネットのお作法じゃないけど
how should I call it, like internet etiquette,
その空気感みたいなのを全然知らなくて
I didn't know the atmosphere or vibe of it at all.
何をして良くて何がしちゃダメみたいなぁ
Like, what was okay to do and what wasn't.
全然分からなくて
I had absolutely no idea.
初心者がネットを使いまくって
So here was a beginner using the internet non-stop,
しかもその場所が匿名掲示板とかいうめちゃくちゃ危ない状況になってて
and on top of that, it was an anonymous message board, which was a super dangerous situation.
自演コメントをしたんじゃよ
So I wrote self-made, sockpuppet comments.
自分を守るようなコメントをしたんじゃが、そしたら
I left comments to defend myself, but then...
自演がバレる系の掲示板だったっぽくて
it turned out to be a board where sockpuppetry easily gets exposed,
他のスレッドとかにも書き込んでたからそういうので照合して
and since I wrote in other threads too, they cross-referenced them,
IPとかそういうので、うーん、何だかよく分かんないんじゃけど、そういうので
using IPs or something like that—I don't really know, but through those means—
同一人物ってバレちゃう系のやつで
it was the type of system where you get outed as the same person, and...
ぶっ叩かれたのじゃ
I got bashed to pieces.
怖かった、あれ本当に怖かったのじゃ
It was scary. That was really terrifying.
な、何でそんな言う？みたいなこといっぱい言われて
I got told so many things like, "W-Why are they saying that?"
わしが人間について詳しくないから、なんでそれがダメか分かんないじゃろうなと思って
Since I didn't know much about humans, I thought I wouldn't understand why it was bad,
人間について知りたくて山から降りたのじゃ
so I came down from the mountain to learn more about humans.
そう、人間の父と母に拾ってもらって
Yes, I was taken in by a human father and mother,
人間として育ててもらったのじゃ
and they raised me as a human.
学校も行ったのじゃ、幼稚園とかから通って
I even went to school, starting from kindergarten,
人間社会で、人間とは何たるかを学んで
and learned what it means to be human in human society.
人間20年生！人間20年生なのじゃ！
A 20-year-old human! I'm a 20-year-old human!
じゃから、これからわしが「父」とか「母」とかそういうワードを使う時は
So from now on, whenever I use words like "father" or "mother,"
わしのことを育ててくれた人間の「父・母」を指すと思って欲しいのじゃ
please know that I'm referring to the human father and mother who raised me.
そして、今ホロライブに入るまでの人生、サラマンダー生みたいなのをまとめた
Also, summarizing my life up until joining Hololive now, my salamander life,
「episode 0」という動画がアップロードされていると思うので
there's a video uploaded called "Episode 0."
もっと気になるよって言う人間たちは、わしのその動画をご覧下さいのじゃ！
So those who are curious to know more, please watch that video of mine!
性格発表しちゃうか！
Shall I announce my personality?
わしは、素直で優しいとっても良い子なのじゃ
I'm a very good girl, honest and kind.
自認ね
Self-proclaimed, that is.
自認ね、自認ね！でね、
Self-proclaimed, okay? Self-proclaimed! And...
マネちゃんと初めて会った時
when I met my manager for the first time,
顔合わせみたいなのがあったんじゃよ、その時に
we had a sort of introductory meeting, and at that time,
自己紹介をするじゃろ？その時に
you introduce yourself, right? At that moment...
「わしは〜優しくて良い子だと思います！」って言ったのじゃ
I said, "I think... I'm a kind and good girl!"
でもね、わし気づいちゃったんじゃがね
But you know, I realized something.
自分で自分のこと優しいって初対面の人間に言う人って、たぶんあんま優しくない
People who call themselves kind to someone they've just met are probably not that kind.
わしさ、シャワー中にさ、わりと一日反省会をするタイプなんじゃが、猛反省した
In the shower, I'm the type who does a self-reflection of the day, and I deeply regretted it.
うわー、あれ失言だったなー。別にわざわざ自分から
"Ugh, that was a slip of the tongue. I didn't need to go out of my way to say..."
いや「良い子」っていうのは他人から見出されるものであって、自分で、自分で、しかも初手で
"No, being a 'good girl' is something others find in you. For me to self-disclose that..."
なんか自己開示するものではなかったかなーと思いながら、髪をわしゃわしゃわしゃって洗ってたのじゃ
"on the very first move wasn't the right way," I thought as I vigorously washed my hair.
どうしよう、マネちゃんに「今わしのことどう思ってる？」って聞いて
What should I do? What if I ask my manager, "What do you think of me now?" and they say...
「いや、良い、まあ、良い子、どうですかね。自分、自分から言うほどじゃないですかね」とか言われたらどうしよう、とか思ってて、まあ、もうしょうがない。しょうがないのじゃ、言ってしまったものはね
"Well, a good... a good girl? I wonder. Isn't it not something you say about yourself?" What if they say that? But well, it can't be helped. It is what it is since I already said it.
めらちゃんは絶対良い子です
"Mera-chan is definitely a good girl."
本当に良い子じゃから、お主らが配信とか動画とか見て、「あ、やっぱめらちゃんは本当に良い子だな」って思ったら
I really am a good girl, so if you guys watch my streams or videos and think, "Ah, Mera-chan really is a good girl after all,"
どの動画にでもいいから「良い子だね」ってコメントを書いて欲しいのじゃ
I want you to comment "You're a good girl" on any of my videos.
そしたらわしは、「あ、やっぱりわしの自認は間違ってなかったんじゃ」って自信に繋がるからな
If you do, it'll boost my confidence, making me feel like, "Ah, my self-assessment wasn't wrong after all."
次！好きなもの！
Next! My favorite things!
好きなもの３つあるから紹介しちゃおうかな
I have three favorite things, so let me introduce them.
好きなもの１つ目！人間！
First favorite thing! Humans!
なんか、人間って個体差凄くない！？あれめっちゃ良いなって思うのじゃ
Like, don't humans have incredible individual differences?! I think that's super cool.
色んな人間と話して来たんじゃが
I've talked to many different humans,
全員違うのじゃ！
and everyone is different!
考え方の癖とか、物事の見え方もだし、喋り方も違うし、誰と喋ってもおもろいのじゃ
Their habits of thought, their perspectives on things, their way of speaking... everyone is so interesting to talk to.
わし本当は全人類と1on1トークしたいのじゃ、ダメかのう？
I actually want to have a 1-on-1 talk with all of humanity. Is that not allowed?
喋るのめっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I really love talking!
で、人間と話すのめっちゃ好きじゃから、こうやってインターネットを通してお主らとコミュニケーション取るのもすごい嬉しいし
And since I love talking to humans so much, I'm super happy to communicate with you guys through the internet like this.
あとわし、人間の言葉がめちゃくちゃ好きで
Also, I absolutely love human words,
Twitter見るのめちゃくちゃ好きで
and I love looking at Twitter.
特に文字ツイート見るのがめちゃくちゃ好きで
I especially love looking at text tweets.
めら組のツイートとかも見るんじゃが
I check tweets from "Mera-gumi" (her fans) too,
この人は何を言うかもだし、何を言わないか、とかもめっちゃ見てて
and I really observe what they say, and even what they choose *not* to say.
このツイートをするってことは、こういうことは思ってそうだけど、でもあえてこういうの言わないんじゃな、とか
"Since they tweeted this, they might think that, but they purposely didn't say it..."
考察するのめちゃくちゃ好きなのじゃ
I absolutely love analyzing all that.
人間の情報が、Twitterってめちゃくちゃ取れてお得なのじゃ
Twitter is great because you can get so much information about humans. It's a bargain!
文字じゃない会話も好きで
I also like non-text conversations,
メンバーと電話するのも凄い好きなのじゃ
and I really love calling other members.
面接めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I also love interviews!
ホロライブのオーディション受けた時も思ったんじゃが
I thought this when I did my Hololive audition, too, but...
面接中って、人間めっちゃ構ってくれるんじゃよ、わしに
during interviews, humans pay so much attention to me.
何言っても熱心に聞いてくれるし、しかも場合によっては
No matter what I say, they listen intently, and sometimes,
何人もの人がわしのこと聞いてくれるし、しかも
multiple people are listening to me, and...
深掘りまでしてくれるのじゃ！「それって、こういうことですか？」みたいな
they even ask follow-up questions! Like, "So does that mean this?"
「そうなのじゃ！そうなのじゃ！」って思うのじゃ
And I'm like, "Exactly! That's it!"
面接週一でしたい
I want to do interviews once a week.
あれぐらい、いっぱい人に構ってほしいのじゃ
That's how much I want people to pay attention to me.
好きなもの２つ目！
Second favorite thing!
ボーカロイドめっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I really love Vocaloids!
合成音声大好きなのじゃ！
I love synthetic voices!
ボカロ曲大好きなのじゃ！
I love Vocaloid songs!
一日中聴いてる
I listen to them all day long.
人間と電話しながら、ボカロ曲聴きながら作業してるのじゃ、これがわしの日常
Calling humans while listening to Vocaloid songs while working—this is my daily life.
好きなボカロPさんいっぱいいるんじゃけど
There are many Vocaloid producers I like,
特にツミキさんっていうボカロPの方がめっちゃ好きで
but I especially love a producer named Tsumiki.
好きなアルバム一選「SAKKAC CRAFT」めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
My favorite album is "SAKKAC CRAFT," I love it so much!
めっちゃかっこいいのじゃ！
It's so cool!
わしあれしか聴いてない
That's the only thing I listen to.
あれしか聴いてないっていうのは、これは、あれ、オタクの嘘、オタクの
Well, "only listening to that" is, you know, an otaku exaggeration...
わし「SAKKAC CRAFT」ってアルバムがガチで大好きなのじゃ。
I really love the album "SAKKAC CRAFT"!
オーディションの書類審査の時に「あなたの好きなものについて語ってください」みたいな質問があって
During the document review phase of the audition, there was a question like "Tell us about something you like."
そこでわしが書いた文章を今日はそのまま貼って良いよって言われたから貼っちゃうのじゃ。
And I was told I could just paste the text I wrote back then, so I'm going to paste it.
さっき言ったツミキさんが書いた、ボカロ曲じゃないんじゃけど、
It's not a Vocaloid song, but Tsukimi-san, whom I mentioned earlier, wrote it.
「トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ」っていう曲がめちゃくちゃ好きで、その曲について書いてみたのじゃ。
I really love the song "Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous," so I wrote about it.
わしのオーディションの時に送った文章を見て欲しいのじゃ。
I want you to see the text I sent during my audition.
ドン！こういう書類は、ですます調で喋ってるのじゃ。
Bam! In these documents, I write in a polite "desu/masu" tone.
さすがにここでね、タメ語ってやつで喋ると、常識が無い奴って思われるからの。
If I used casual speech here, people would think I have no common sense.
のじゃ略でお送りさせていただいておりますが、
So, even though I've omitted my usual "noja" style...
こんな感じで書いて送ったのじゃ。
...this is how I wrote and sent it.
これくらいわしは、そしてボカロPさんが作曲した曲が大好きなのじゃ！
That's how much I love Vocaloid, and songs composed by Vocaloid producers!
そして、好きなもの丸３！なろう系！
And, my favorite thing #3! "Narou" (web novel) series!
なろう系めっちゃ好きなのじゃ！
I really love Narou novels!
味方が誰も死なない、あんまり苦しいハラハラが無いというか、
Nobody on the ally side dies, and there's not much painful suspense.
ずっと気持ちよく勝ち続けるみたいな、成り上がりって感じじゃから、
It's like a rising-up story where they keep winning comfortably.
見ててずっと気持ちいいのじゃ。
It always feels satisfying to watch.
不安な気持ちにならない内容が多いから、元気ない時とかに、
Since many of them don't make you feel anxious, when I'm feeling down...
「今日は元気ないからお布団で一日ぐーたらしてようかな」って日とかに、
...or on days when I think, "I have no energy, so I'll just laze in bed all day,"
ずーっとなろう系ばっかり読んでる。ずーっと同じのばっかり読んでるのじゃ。
I spend the whole time reading Narou novels. I just read the same ones over and over.
なろう系以外にも、結構漫画自体が好きで、なんか少年ジャンプの作品とかも好きなのじゃ。
Besides Narou, I generally like manga, like works from Shonen Jump.
アニメとか漫画は、わし、この辺が好きなのじゃ。
As for anime and manga, these are the ones I like.
怖いもの発表しようかな！
Shall I announce the things I'm afraid of?
怖いもの一！サーモン！
Fear #1: Salmon!
サーモンって怖くないですか？
Isn't salmon terrifying?
なんか、わしちっちゃい頃はね、焼き鮭を結構食べてたんじゃよ。焼き鮭大好きで、
You see, when I was little, I used to eat a lot of grilled salmon. I loved grilled salmon.
初めて回転寿司に行った時に、わしは英語をちょっと分かってたから、
When I went to a conveyor belt sushi restaurant for the first time, because I knew a bit of English...
あの、サーモンっていう文字を見て、「あ、これは鮭じゃ」と思って、
...I saw the word "salmon" and thought, "Ah, this is salmon (shake)!"
鮭大好きじゃから、この回転寿司でもサーモンとやらを食べてみようではないかと思ってね、お皿を取るじゃないですか。
Since I loved shake, I thought I'd try this "salmon" thing at the conveyor belt sushi, and took a plate.
焼き鮭だと思って、サーモンを食べるじゃないですか。
Believing it was grilled salmon, I ate the salmon.
頭がバグって、
My brain glitched...
「なんじゃ！」と思って。「わしが今まで食べてたあの魚は何処へ！」と思って、
...and I was like, "What on earth?! Where did the fish I've been eating all this time go?!"
そこからずっと怖いのじゃ。
Ever since then, it has been terrifying.
何が起きてるか分かんなくて、なんか「これが来る！これが来る！」と思って食べてみたら、全然違う！
I didn't understand what was happening. I expected "this" flavor, but when I ate it, it was completely different!
しかも！しかもなんか濡れてた！しっとりしてる。
And! And it was somehow wet! It was moist.
しばらくは、そっからサーモンが食べれなかったのじゃ。怖すぎて。
For a while after that, I couldn't eat salmon. It was too scary.
最初から別物だと思って食べれば怖くないと思って、そっからは普通に食べれるのじゃ。
But then I realized if I ate it knowing it's a completely different thing, it wouldn't be scary. Since then, I can eat it normally.
今では毎回お寿司屋さん行ったらサーモン食べるくらい好きではあるんじゃよ。
Now, I love it enough to order salmon every time I go to a sushi place.
好きなのじゃ。好きじゃけど、怖くて、「なんじゃー！」と思いながらいつも食べてる。
I like it. I like it, but it's scary, and I'm always eating it while thinking, "What is this?!"
怖いものその２、トースター！
Fear #2: The Toaster!
これはもう説明不要な気がするのじゃ。
I feel like this one doesn't even need an explanation.
トースターって怖くない？
Isn't the toaster scary?
わしパン好きなんじゃが、トースターって急に出てきて怖い。
I love bread, but the toaster is scary because it suddenly pops out.
「はわわわっ」てなるのじゃ。
It makes me go, "Hawawawa!"
焼き上がりました、「ぬるぬるぬるぬる〜」って出てきてくれたら、わしだって「あ、焼き上がったな」って思うんじゃが、
If it finished baking and slid out slowly, I'd just think, "Ah, it's done baking."
なんか「バッ！」って出てくるから、「ひゃあ！」ってなるのじゃ。あれやめてほしい。
But it suddenly goes "Bam!" and pops out, so I jump. I wish it wouldn't do that.
びっくりさせるのずるいのじゃ。
Startling me like that is unfair.
怖いもの丸３、炎上。
Fear #3: Internet Flame Wars.
炎上ガチで怖いのじゃ。やめてほしいのじゃ。
Flame wars are seriously scary. I want them to stop.
人生で初めて触ったインターネットで、叩かれを経験してるから、めっちゃ過剰に恐れてる気がするのじゃ。
Because I experienced being bashed when I first used the internet, I think I'm excessively afraid of it.
初手で山特定されてますからね、こっちとら。
My home mountain was identified right from the start, after all.
「お前住んでる山ここだろ」言われてますからね。ガチ怖かったよ、あれ。外出れんよ。
They were like, "The mountain you live on is this one, right?" That was seriously scary. I couldn't go outside.
インターネットって、ルールとか、ある程度空気感とかあるじゃろ？
The internet has its own rules and general atmosphere, right?
あれ、初見殺しだと思うのじゃ、わし。
I think it's a beginner trap.
アクセスする難易度って低いじゃろ？見るのも楽しく見れるじゃろ？書き込むのも簡単じゃろ？
The barrier to entry is low, right? It's fun to watch, and it's easy to post things, right?
初めてインターネット触ったのに書き込めたよ？書き込めたのに、ダメだった。
I was able to post even though it was my first time using the internet! I posted, and yet, it was a disaster.
もっとさ、ルールとか書いて欲しいよね。「〇〇はこうしてください！こういうことはしちゃいけません！」みたいなの全部書いて欲しいのじゃ！
I wish they would write down the rules more clearly. I want them to write down everything, like "Do this!" or "Don't do that!"
だからすっごい気をつけようと思うのじゃ。火消し屋じゃし。
So, I'm going to be extremely careful. Since I'm a firefighter.
わしの夢！わしの夢は、人間に恩返しをすることなのじゃ。
My dream! My dream is to give back to humans.
人間として20年間生きてきて、仲間に入れてもらえたのがめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったのじゃ。
Living as a human for 20 years, I was so incredibly happy to be accepted as one of you.
200年くらいずっとひとりぼっちじゃたし、ずっと寂しかったから、
I had been all alone for about 200 years, and I was always lonely...
構ってもらえたのがすごく嬉しくて、人間好きなのじゃ。
...so I was really happy that people paid attention to me. I love humans.
わしも、かつてのわしみたいに、今居場所がなくて一人で寂しいって思ってる人間が、もしかしたらいるかもしれないと思って、
I thought there might be humans out there who, like I used to be, have no place to belong and feel lonely and alone right now...
わしはそんな人間の居場所になりたいのじゃ。
...and I want to become a place of belonging for those people.
次はわしが居場所になることによって、人間に恩を返していくという作戦なのじゃ。
The plan is for me to give back to humans by becoming a place of belonging next.
そしてインターネットで、やっぱ、わしかつて痛い目に遭いましたから、
And on the internet, since I once learned my lesson the hard way...
どんな人間にも優しい、インターネット1年生でも、初心者の人々でも入りやすい、そんな配信や動画を作りたいのじゃ。
...I want to create streams and videos that are kind to everyone, and easy to join even for internet beginners and newcomers.
あったかい居場所にしたいのじゃ。
I want to make it a warm place to belong.
お主ら協力してくれるかの？協力して欲しいのじゃ。
Will you all cooperate with me? I'd love for you to cooperate.
いかがでしたでしょうか。わしの自己紹介動画見て、
How was it? After watching my self-introduction video...
熱干めらというサラマンダーがどんな子なのか、ちょっとは分かってくれたかの？
...did you understand a little bit about what kind of girl the salamander Mera Atsui is?
これから、配信とか動画とか見て、もっと色んなわしのことを知っていって欲しいなとは思いつつ、
While hoping you'll watch my streams and videos and get to know more about me from now on...
この自己紹介動画さえ見てれば
If you just watch this self-introduction video...
まぁあちちめら、9割ぐらい分かったと言っても
...you could say you understand 90% of Achichimera,
過言ではないぐらいな内容な気がする
and it wouldn't be an exaggeration, I feel.
過言か？過言か。過言かあ、ははは！
Is it an exaggeration? Is it? It is? Ahahaha!
楽しんでもらえたなら幸いなのじゃ！
I'd be happy if you enjoyed it!
そして最後に一言
And lastly, one word.
わし運命を信じてるのじゃ
I believe in fate.
人生ってさ、その時その時で出会うべき人がいるじゃないですか？
You know, in life, there are people you are meant to meet at certain times, right?
それがお主らににとっての、その時出会うべきだった人が
If, for you all, that person you were meant to meet at that time...
わしじゃったら良いなあって思うんじゃよ
...was me, that would make me so happy.
あちちめらと出会ってから
"Since meeting Achichimera,"
すごい毎日楽しくなって
"every day has become so much fun,"
居場所になったよ
"and it has become a place where I belong."
って思ってくれる人間が
If there's even one person...
1人でもいっぱいいたら
...who feels that way,
わしはここにきた意味があったなって思うし
I'll feel like coming here was worth it,
そうなるようにこれから
and to make that happen, from now on...
お主らににとっての温かい居場所になることを願って、活動していきます！
I'll keep working hard, hoping to be a warm place where you belong!
チャンネル登録とか、高評価、コメントとか、わしを応援して欲しいのじゃ～！
Please support me by subscribing, leaving high ratings, and commenting!
いろんな方法で、わしのこと応援してくれると、とっても嬉しいのじゃ
Supporting me in various ways would make me so happy!
ボイスなどデビュー記念で様々なものが販売中なので
Also, various debut commemorative items, like voice packs, are on sale,
チェックしてみて欲しいのじゃ～！
so please check them out!
ということで、今日の動画はおしまいなのじゃ！
With that, today's video comes to an end!
また動画とか配信とか、色んなところで、お主と会えると嬉しいのじゃ！
I hope to see you again in videos, streams, and other places!
これからよろしくね！
Please look after me from now on!
また次の何かでお会いしましょ～！
Let's meet again in the next video or stream!
ばいばいなのじゃ～！
Bye-bye~!